Harish Sharma

+91- 9143180183

<u>Harisharma9332@gmail.com</u>

<u>https://harissha.github.io/</u>

Lead Java Spring Boot Microservice Developer (9yrs of exp. in IT Industry) specializing in Back End development. Experienced with all stages of the Project Life Cycle for dynamic web projects in Analysis, design, Development of large Data Systems by creating an intuitive architecture and Real time streaming ETL pipelines. Well-versed in numerous programming languages and technologies including JAVA, SPRINGBOOT, MONGODB, KAFKA, ELK STACK, HTML, OOP, JavaScript, CSS, MySQL.



Experience

06/2022 to present

Senior System Analyst IBM India Private Limited

IBM Agent Assist Project Mar 2023 - Present

Agent Assist is a Platform as a Service (PaaS) solution that simplifies the process of building information collections. It enables you to locate, review, enhance, and track high-quality and highly relevant information for use by cognitive systems. In doing so, it reduces the work of identifying and managing the highest quality content by using a guided and repeatable process that makes subject matter experts more efficient and allows them to focus on what is most important.

Responsibilities

- Lead the Backend team with innovation.
- Create, Update Spring Boot Microservices Api to be consumed by UI portal service.

Singlife Retail Claim Jun 2022 - Mar 2023

Singlife Retail Claim is an insurance website portal for Singlife customers. This portal helps in smooth transfer and claim of different insurance policies to its policy holders, made available by Singlife.

Responsibilities

- Lead the Backend team with innovation.
- Create, Update Spring Boot Microservices Api to be consumed by UI portal service.

Skills

- PROJECT MANAGEMENT
- JAVA
- SPRINGBOOT
- MySQL
- MONGODB
- ORACLEDB
- KAFKA
- ELK STACK
- HTML
- CSS
- GIT
- JENKINS
- RUNDECK
- OPENSHIFT CONTAINERS(OC)

Certifications

- Google Project
 Management Certificate
 Click to Verify
- Microservices Architecture <u>Click to Verify</u>
- Enterprise Design Thinking Click to Verify

04/2021 to 05/2022

Senior Associate

PricewaterhouseCoopers(PwC)

Global Data Hub(GDH) Apr 2021 - May 2022

Global Data Hub is like a PwC Data center where all customer and client related financial and non-financial data is stored. We were entrusted and responsible for handling all these data.

Responsibilities

- Lead the Team with innovation.
- Procure and establish different environments for server, interacting with different team and stake holders on need basis.
- Create, Update Spring Boot Microservices to be consumed by UI portal service.
- Install and setup different software in env. platforms such as NGINX, NODE.js, NPM, PM2 services.
- Develop graphical representation of customer and client data in POWER BI.

01/2019 to 03/2021

Technology Analyst

Infosys Ltd.

Apple Talent Portal Sep 2020 – Mar 2021

Apple Talent Portal is a portal through which Apple manages it's Talent Pool e.g Requisition, Offer, Internal Job Postings, Profile of Candidate.

Responsibilities

- Develop Java based Spring Boot Microservice Api's.
- Scan and improve existing Microservice Api's using SonarQube.

HONOR AWARDS

- Awarded for Most Spirited Team in Q1,2018-2019.
- Awarded for Outstanding Performance and Dedication by Cisco Systems in 2018.
- Awarded for Most Spirited Team in Q1,2017-2018.
- Awarded Highest Scorer for Science in Higher Secondary Examination 2011.

Education

- Bachelor of Technology (B.TECH):
 ECE – 2015 with 8.1 CGPA BPPIMT, Kolkata.
- Higher Secondary School: with an aggregate of 79% National High School, Kolkata.
- Secondary School: with an aggregate of 78% National High School, Kolkata.

01/2019 to 03/2021

Technology Analyst

Infosys Ltd.

Cisco CSC *Apr* 2020 – *Sep* 2020

Cisco CSC is an addendum to Cisco Service Portal, ensuring ease of access and availability of Cisco Products to Cisco Customers.

Responsibilities

- Migrate 2.5 Billion of Cisco Customer Records safely, securely from OracleDb to Cloud Atlas MongoDb using Java based Cisco Migration Tool known as SyncTool.
- Modify existing SyncTool code for accommodating changes for Cloud Atlas MongoDb instead of On Premise MongoDb.

Cisco BroadSoft Dec 2019 - Apr 2020

Cisco BroadSoft was responsible for adding of four new product entitlements, which resulted in classification and addition of Customer into four different Container Id, apart from Smart and Virtual Container Ids.

Responsibilities

- Enhance and Deploy an existing Cisco Java based Migration Tool known as SyncTool.
- After accommodating the changes, I was responsible for migration of data from OracleDb to MongoDb using Java.

Cisco AuditLog Aug 2019 – Dec 2019

Cisco AuditLog was responsible for displaying Customer related data based on their Subscription of choice of Cisco Products Plan opted by Cisco Customers.

Responsibilities

- Develop two Java based MultiThreaded Application Programs with dynamic requirements coming in for Data Migration from OracleDb to Kafka.
- First Application Program was based on migration of changed or updated records coming into OracleDb to MongoDb using Java.
- Later Application Program was based on migration of changed or updated documents coming into MongoDb as a result of First Application Program to Kafka using Java.

01/2018 to 12/2018

Senior Systems Engineer Infosys Ltd.

Cisco PAL Dec 2018 – Aug 2019

Cisco PAL is a Reporting Dashboard used to display different kinds of interrelated Customer Data based on products bought by Cisco Customers and also any Support Cases raised and tracking of stages in which the Support Case is pending, via Cisco Support Portal.

Responsibilities

- Lead, Develop and Design, Graphical representation of Reporting Dashboard Web Pages in AngularJS 7 using Kibana, MongoDB, BootStrap, TypeScript, CSS3 and backend API included validating, displaying and download of excel reports functionality using SpringBoot.
- Two of my subordinates were assigned to me for completion of this project.

Cisco CCCM Nov 2018 - Dec 2018

Cisco CCCM provides a mechanism to validate Cisco Clients for authenticity. It provides authentication mechanism based on API request to send and further investigate on the case or concern raised by Cisco Clients with Cisco Products.

Responsibilities

- Develop a SpringBoot API within a very short span of time, validate the Client details provided in Request Body and pass on these details to respective Kafka Topics for further investigation.
- This API was developed using Java, SpringBoot, Kafka.

Cisco MEU Aug 2018 - Nov 2018

Cisco MEU was responsible for allowing Cisco Customers to view only their own groups and allow, support features such as entitlements to raise a case against their product which were either bought, subscribed or of freemium version.

Responsibilities

 My responsibilities included to Develop Java based Application Program for Data Migration from OracleDb to Elastic Search by using OracleDb, MongoDb, Java, Kafka, Logstash and Elastic Search.

12/2015 to 12/2017

System Engineer Infosys Ltd.

Cisco DUET RMA Mar 2018 – Aug 2018

Cisco DUET RMA maintains customer data and keeps record and track Cisco Products being sold to Cisco Customers.

Responsibilities

 Develop and Deploy Logstash based scripts for Data Migration from OracleDb to Elastic Search by using OracleDb, Logstash, Kafka, Elastic Search.

Cisco Entitlement Base May 2017 - Mar 2018

Cisco Entitlement Base apart from maintaining Customer Data, keeps records of the Cisco Product being sold and also provide Customer Support for Cisco Products sold and subscribed via Software Download Center, a part of SWC project.

Responsibilities

 Develop and enhance multiple Web API using Node.js, MongoDb, SpringBoot and also to Develop and enhance multiple Java based Application Program for Data Migration from OracleDb to Elastic Search by using OracleDb, MongoDb, Java 8, Kafka, Logstash and Elastic Search.

Cisco 902 Nov 2016 – May 2017

Cisco 902 was a Dashboard to view Case, its Assignee, its Completion Time, its Status and others, by which we can keep track of the time taken by Assignee to complete a particular case assigned to him or her, raised by Cisco Clients.

Responsibilities

 Develop and Design the UI of this Dashboard along with other developers by using HTML, CSS, TypeScript, AngularJS 2, JAVA and MySQL.

Declaration

I, Harish Sharma, do hereby confirm that the information given above is true to the best of my knowledge.

DATE: 12-October-2023

PLACE: Kolkata